alarm.com 2019-12-07

# Privacy Policy

#### **Alarm.com's Privacy Policy**

 **Our Privacy Mission**  
We are sensitive to the private nature of the information you, our service providers, partners, end-users and prospective end-user customers provide to us. Our Privacy Policy is designed to maximize your ability to protect your personal, private data while at the same time allowing us to provide you with the best interactive security, energy management, video monitoring, automation and wellness services possible. This Privacy Policy states our privacy practices for your use of (i) this website and any mobile sites or applications operated by Alarm.com (the “User Interfaces”) and (ii) any combination of products and services we provide or that can be purchased or accessed via any User Interface (the “Services”). 

Alarm.com’s Services are provided by licensed and authorized service providers (referred to as “Authorized Service Providers” or “Alarm.com Dealers”). If you are a customer of an Authorized Service Provider, your information will be processed by Alarm.com acting as a data processor and your Authorized Service Provider will remain responsible for the handling of any personal information it collects from you and for compliance with any applicable data protection and/or privacy laws. Please read the Privacy Policy carefully.

 **For Data Subjects in the European Economic Area ("EEA") and Switzerland**  
If you are located in the EEA or Switzerland, our ["Privacy Notice to Data Subjects in the EEA and Switzerland"](https://www.alarm.com/legal/eea-policy) provides additional information about your use of the User Interfaces and Services and your rights as data subjects residing in Switzerland or the EEA, which includes all countries in the European Union, Liechtenstein, Iceland and Norway. 

**Information Collection and Use**  
Alarm.com collects and stores certain information from or about you that can be used to uniquely contact, identify, or locate you ("Personal Information"). 

When using the User Interfaces, you may provide us with Personal Information including, but not limited to, your name, home or business address, phone number, email address, location, or zip code. 

When using our Services, you or your Authorized Service Provider may provide us with certain additional information (e.g., unit description, home or business size, home or business system configuration, sensor names, appliances or other devices monitored by Alarm.com, account information, schedule, mode, automation settings, and device settings) in order for us to personalize your Services. Alarm.com may also receive Personal Information that you have provided to our partners, including emergency contact information and user profile information, to enable Alarm.com to provide our Services. 

Alarm.com may process information regarding your use of the Alarm.com Services, including but not limited to: performance of any security or other device monitored by Alarm.com, electrical usage or consumption, heating and cooling information, light or other fixture settings, and usage and alert logs. We receive this type of information from your devices that are monitored by Alarm.com and your computer or other electronic device through which you may access, browse, download, receive, or otherwise use the Alarm.com User Interfaces or Services (each a "Personal Device"), and we may also receive and process such information from third parties.

 **Location-based Information**  
Some features of our Services, such as location-activated arming reminders, thermostat adjustments, vehicle diagnostics, and other location-based Services (collectively, “GeoServices”), use location information. Before certain GeoServices information can be used, you must first opt-in to activate these Services. If you enable these features, we will automatically collect and store location information from your Personal Device or vehicle you designate which is capable of producing location data (e.g., mobile device, GPS device, or vehicle). This location information may include your current location or places you have recently visited. We also may aggregate this information for Alarm.com's internal purposes and to provide information requested by you. If you do not wish for us to collect and store this information, do not enable these features.

 **Video and Audio Data**  
When you (i) subscribe to Alarm.com’s video monitoring or video monitoring add-on Services (such as the Visual Verification services), (ii) use a connected doorbell, camera, image sensor, or other connected device or wearable that is capable of recording video and/or audio recordings, or (iii) subscribe to emergency two-way voice services, you are enabling us, certain of our third-party service providers, or your central station, to record, store, view and process video and/or audio recordings from your monitoring equipment. This may include capturing and sending you portions of this data as part of a notification or analyzing the data to identify motion or other events. We may process information from your monitoring equipment so that we can send you alerts. In addition, if you have the recording features enabled, we will capture, process and store video and audio data recordings from your device and you may be able to access those recordings. 

Data protection and privacy laws in your country may impose certain responsibilities on you and your use of security cameras, connected doorbells and other devices with recording capabilities. You (not Alarm.com) are responsible for ensuring that you comply with any applicable laws. For example, you may need to display a notice that alerts visitors to your home or business that they may be recorded using security cameras and other devices with recording capabilities. Alarm.com takes no responsibility for your compliance with these laws.

 **Information Sharing**  
Alarm.com will not disclose your Personal Information to any other entity except:

  * as is necessary to provide the Alarm.com User Interfaces and Services to you;

  * to your Authorized Service Provider, the company through which you subscribed to our Services;

  * to the central station selected by your Authorized Service Provider to receive alarm signals and coordinate emergency response;

  * when you have opted in to share the information;

  * when we need to share the information with an entity who works on our behalf to provide the Services (these entities do not have any right to use the Personal Information beyond what is necessary for the purpose of fulfilling the agreement we have with them);

  * if you are an existing user of Alarm.com Services, to provide notifications of additional Alarm.com-supported products or Services that may be of interest to you;

  * as necessary in connection with other lawful business purposes; and

  * as otherwise necessary when required or permitted by law.

In addition, we may disclose your information when the information has been converted to a form that cannot be used to identify you. It may also be necessary for us to disclose your Personal Information in case of a merger or combination with, or acquisition of a portion of our business by, another company or entity, in which case Personal Information collected by Alarm.com would be expected to be one of the transferred business assets.

 **Information Protection**  
Alarm.com has security measures in place to protect against the loss, misuse, and alteration of your Personal Information. For example, we protect your information through a unique username and password, and we protect certain sensitive communications with our website through server authentication and secure connections. However, no method of data transmission is completely secure.

 **Right to Access, Correct and Delete Personal Information**  
If you are an existing or potential end-user of Alarm.com Services and have entered Personal Information directly through our website, you may request to correct or delete your Personal Information by contacting us at privacy@alarm.com.   
If you are an existing end-user of Services you may view, update, or delete certain Personal Information at any time by following the links at www.alarm.com to your profile and address book pages. These changes will be immediately made to our records. If you wish to stop Services notifications, you may do so through the User Interfaces. For customers of Authorized Service Providers, changes you make to your user profile on the Alarm.com User Interfaces to your user profile may not automatically change the records of your Authorized Service Provider. You should contact your Authorized Service Provider directly to make changes to its records.

 **Cookies, Web Beacons and Website Analytics**  
We employ "cookie" technology and "web beacons" to help you move faster through the User Interfaces, to help improve the functionality of the User Interfaces, to collect information for advertising of our Services and to optimize your use of our User Interfaces. A cookie is a string of information sent by a User Interface and stored on your hard drive or temporarily in your Personal Device's memory. A "web beacon" is an electronic image placed in the code of a web page. Our third-party suppliers, subcontractors or business partners may employ cookies and web beacons to tailor Alarm.com's advertising to the interests of its users and target audience, monitor the traffic patterns of users from one Alarm.com page to another or to improve site performance. We also use cookies to identify you on future visits to our site and to other sites. When you access the Alarm.com User Interfaces, we place a cookie on your computer. This allows the User Interfaces to recognize you as you navigate through the User Interfaces. At your discretion, Alarm.com may store and access cookies on your Personal Device to allow you to bypass the process of re-entering certain information each time you access the Alarm.com website. You can also delete cookies from your website browser at any time.

We may collect information relating to customer trends and patterns and use cookies and software tools to measure site usage and related information.

We may also permit third parties to place or modify cookies on your Personal Device on our behalf. The third parties can use these "tracking cookies" (also known as "third party cookies") to determine if you have visited certain pages on our site or other sites and may use tracking cookies to present targeted advertisements to you as you visit other sites. These tracking cookies do not contain personally identifiable information (though they do identify the Personal Device that you use to visit the site) and you can configure your browser to reject tracking cookies.

If you access our Services or the User Interfaces through your Personal Device, we may automatically collect certain information about your Personal Device that could include usage information and statistics, an IP address, Personal Device type and model, browser type, device ID, domain names, access times, referring website addresses, Personal Device settings and history, and other information collected about your access of the User Interfaces or receipt of communications or notification from Alarm.com.

Our website and mobile apps may use Google Analytics, a web analysis service provided by Google, in order to better understand your use of our website and mobile apps and how we can improve them. Google Analytics collects information such as how often users visit a website, what pages you visit when you do so, and what other websites you used prior to coming to such website. Google Analytics collects only the IP address assigned to you on the date you visit a website, rather than your name or other identifying information. We do not combine the information collected through the use of Google Analytics with your Personal Information. Although Google Analytics plants a permanent cookie on your web browser to identify you as a unique user the next time you visit a website, the cookie cannot be used by anyone but Google. Google's ability to use and share information collected by Google Analytics about your visits to our website is restricted by the [Google Analytics Terms of Use](https://www.google.com/analytics/terms/us.html) and the [Google Privacy Policy](https://policies.google.com/privacy?hl=en&gl=us). Google utilizes the data collected to track and examine the use of our website, to prepare reports on its activities and share them with other Google services. Google may use the data collected on our website to contextualize and personalize the ads of its own advertising network. To more fully understand how Google may use the data it collects on the Client websites, please review "How Google uses data when you use our partners' sites or apps," (located at <https://policies.google.com/technologies/partner-sites> or any successor URL).

 **Third Party Websites**  
For your convenience, some hyperlinks may be posted on the Alarm.com website that link to other websites not under Alarm.com's control. Alarm.com is not responsible for, and this Privacy Policy does not apply to, the privacy practices of those sites or of any companies that Alarm.com does not own or control. Alarm.com does not endorse any of these websites or pages, the services or products described or offered on such sites or pages, or any of the content contained on those sites or pages. Alarm.com encourages you to seek out and read the privacy policy of each website that you visit. In addition, should you happen to initiate a transaction on a website linked to the Alarm.com website, even if you reached that site through the Alarm.com User Interfaces, the information that you submit to complete that transaction becomes subject to the privacy practices of the operator of that linked website. You should read that website's privacy policies to understand how Personal Information that is collected about you is used and protected.

 **Utilizing our User Interfaces from Outside of the United States**  
If you are utilizing our User Interfaces from outside the United States, please be aware that your information may be transferred to, stored or processed in the United States, where our servers are located and our central database is operated. The data protection and other laws of the United States and other countries might not be as comprehensive as those in your country, but please be assured that we take steps to protect your privacy. Our offices and data centers are located in the United States, so some of your Personal Information will be transferred to the United States in connection with your use of the Services. If you are located in the EEA or Switzerland, then the [Privacy Notice to Data Subjects in the EEA and Switzerland](https://www.alarm.com/legal/eea-policy) also applies to your use of the User Interfaces.

Alarm.com uses European Commission-approved "Standard Contractual Clauses" or "Model Clauses" and is also certified under the EU-U.S. Privacy Shield and U.S.-Swiss Privacy Shield Frameworks (as described in our [Privacy Shield Privacy Notice](http://www.alarm.com/legal/privacy-shield-policy)) for the transfer of Personal Information from the EEA or Switzerland to the United States. To learn more about the EU-U.S. or U.S.-Swiss Privacy Shield Framework and to view our certification, please visit www.privacyshield.gov. 

**Privacy Policy Changes**  
We may change this Privacy Policy at any time. Any changes to this Privacy Policy will be posted on our User Interfaces. The most recent version of this Privacy Policy is reflected by the version date located below. This Privacy Policy is not intended to and does not create any contractual or other legal right in or on behalf of any party.

 **California and Delaware Do Not Track Disclosures**  
California and Delaware law require Alarm.com to indicate whether it honors "Do Not Track" settings in your browser concerning targeted advertising. "Do Not Track" is a standard that is currently under development. As that standard is not yet finalized, Alarm.com adheres to the standards set out in this Privacy Policy and does not monitor or follow any Do Not Track browser requests.

 **Contact Information**  
If you have any questions, concerns, or suggestions regarding this Privacy Policy, please contact us at:

privacy@alarm.com   
or  
Alarm.com Incorporated – Privacy  
8281 Greensboro Drive, Suite 100  
Tysons, VA 22102  
USA

Last updated: May 23, 2018
